### **SERGEI STAROV**

Oakland, CA • C: (702) 572-7335 • E: <u>starovdev@gmail.com</u>

• <a href="https://starovsergei.github.io/personal-page/">https://starovsergei.github.io/personal-page/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

Professional Software Development Engineer in Test with over 7 years of experience in software development, web, mobile automation and managing QA teams. I have hired and managed cross-border, cross-functional QA talent in US and India to deliver best-in-class product experience with full range of testing across all levels of test pyramid (from functional, UI, integration to unit tests)

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming:** Python, JavaScript, React, Java, HTML & CSS, Ruby, C/C++

**Automation**: Selenium WebDriver, Cypress, Postman, Jasmine, Jest, Mocha,

Jenkins, TestNG, JUnit, Maven, Appium, Gradle, Sauce Labs, Git

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## TestPro, Sunnyvale, CA Software Automation Engineer

January 2020 – present

- Developed Test Automation framework for UI testing from scratch using Python, Selenium WebDriver, Jenkins, Sauce Labs
- Created test strategies and set up infrastructure test automation for web and mobile platforms.
- Own end-to-end QA process, black, grey and white box testing methodologies and mentoring
- Mentoring junior QA engineers.

# Auto Club of Southern California (AAA), Los Angeles, CA Software Engineer February 2018 – January 2020

- Developed applications for online insurance products exclude/remove/add drivers from auto insurance policy with React, Javascript, Typescript used by hundreds of thousands customers.
- Developed and maintained unit tests using Jasmine, Jest, Mocha frameworks following TDD practices and mock testing techniques
- Evaluated applications' code in compliance with OWASP security practices and eliminated vulnerabilities

- Built QA team by leading the hiring, training process and managing both onsite and offshore teams
- Created automation test suites for UI and RESTful services using Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, TestRail and Java, automation solutions for CI/CD process with Jenkins, Maven, Selenium Grid, AWS. As a result, time to verify new builds/releases has been significantly reduced (up to 80%).
- Developed efficient and secure internal tool for back-end API testing (integration testing)
- Developed and maintained application for performance/load testing of company servers.

## CreativeDrive, Hollywood, FL Software Automation Engineer

**August 2015 – April 2016** 

- Created more than 300 automated scripts for testing CreativeDrive asset management release software using Selenium WebDriver, Java and JUnit
- Work with technical leads from development and DevOps on the overall test automation ecosystem across engineering practice with effective CI/CD strategies
- Worked closely with Dev, PM teams in an agile setting with two weeks sprint planning, retrospective and daily standups.

## **EDUCATION**

<b>BA</b> in Legal Studies, Herzen State University, St. Petersburg, Russia	2010-2014
Computer Science Certificate, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL	2016-2017
Computer Programming Extension, University of California Santa Cruz, CA	2020-2021